Praise the living Jesus.
If you're happy to be in the presence of God, put your hands together for our Lord Jesus.
If you believe today is your day, put your hands together for our Lord Jesus.
Yes, greet your neighbours; say, "You are welcome to the presence of God".
You are welcome to the presence of God.
Viewers all over the world, we welcome you, in Jesus' name.
You may be seated.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Praise the Lord.
The Bible says that the essence of true worship is in honouring God
with what our lives depend on.
Once again, I greet you all in the name of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ.
How many of us love the Lord with all our heart?
How many of us love the Lord with all our strength?
With all our quality time - how many of us?
All our localty and substance - how many of us?
Well, it is good to see the raised hands.
But you know the answer to this question is more of the heart and a call for self-examination.
Ask yourself, "Do I really love God?"
Now ask your neighbour, "Do you really love God?"
You can see that the answer to the question is more of the heart and a call for self-examination.
God is concerned about you.
The Bible says He is busy planting the seeds of what you are becoming, if you love in truth.
In John 17:18, Jesus said to all His disciples, believers, Christians:
As the Father has sent me, so send I you - to love one another, just as I love you.
This statement was a kind of commissioning in all believers, thus giving them a pattern of operation.
In other words, Jesus was simply saying:
As my Father has commissioned me to be a solution to everyone in trouble,
so have I commissioned you as a solution.
Every person you meet today is trying to change their life in some way
but they don't just know how to.
Some want their health to be improved; others want financial freedom.
No matter your status in life - are you rich or poor?
No matter your status in life - are you strong or weak?
Are you educated or uneducated?
Someone is waiting for a lifeline from you, for you to put a quality smile on their face.
Therefore, do not allow your social, political, economic, cultural or religious background
to rob you of your love for Christ - I mean your love for one another.
Today, we claim we love God, yet our heart is full of offence,
making it difficult to love one another.
That is why Jesus says in Matthew 25, I was hungry - you gave me no food.
I was thirsty - you gave me no water.
I was a stranger - you did not take me in.
I was naked - you did not clothe me.
I was sick in prison - you did not visit me.
On that occasion His disciples asked, Master, when were you naked?
When were you thirsty and when were you hungry?
Jesus replied: When you stood in the midst of the lowly, those who could not help themselves.
Maybe you only imagine you are in the company of the poor, the uneducated, the destitute,
the weak and disadvantaged people.
Don't be surprised when you eventually realise, perhaps too late,
that it was Jesus Himself whom you denied.
That is why I tell you that do not allow your social, political, economic,
religious and cultural background to rob you of your love for Christ.
I mean your love for one another.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Today we all desire to reap but the question is: What have we planted?
If you plant love, the Bible says, you will reap love
because there is no loving in truth that does not express itself in giving.
There is no giving in truth without receiving.
The Bible says that true blessing actually comes from giving.
If you truly possess love - which is one of the fruits of the Spirit - the nature of God -
you will not look to the other side when your fellow brothers are in need.
This is compromise.
Many today believe that they can only give out of abundance, when they have surplus,
when they have plenty, when they are healed,
when they are blessed, when they have a breakthrough.
But this is a false belief.
Ask the poor widow in the book of 1 Kings 17
and she will tell you that everyone has something to give, no matter how small or big.
That is why Prophet T.B. Joshua says and I quote:
Your idea of 'if only I add money' keeps robbing you of your blessings.
Your idea of 'if I were strong' keeps robbing you of your strength.
Your idea of 'if I were free' keeps robbing you of your freedom.
Your idea of 'if I had money, I would give to the poor, I would help the weak,
if I were strong, I would help the less privileged, I would help the weak'...
The danger here is that if you fail to help from the little God has blessed you with, more may never come.
If you fail to help from the little strength God has given you, more may never come.
Brethren, help and be helped, when you help for God's sake.
Tell your neighbour, "Help and be helped, when you help for God's sake".
Love and receive love, when you love for God's sake.
This will bring me to the title of my message: "The Secret of Abundance".
Tell your neighbour, "The Secret of Abundance".
God is concerned about our growth.
Quickly turn with me to the Book of Galatians and that will be our first proof text for this message.
The Book of Galatians 6.
Let's take our reading from verse 6.
Are you there?
"Let him who is taught the word share in all good things with him who teaches.
Do not be deceived, God is not mocked; for whatever a man sows, that he will also reap.
For he who sows to his flesh will of the flesh reap corruption,
but he sows to the Spirit will of the Spirit reap everlasting life."
Verse 9.
"And let us not grow weary while doing good,
for in due season we shall reap if we do not lose heart.
Therefore, as we have opportunity, let us do good to all,
especially to those who are of the household of faith."
Let us read that verse 10 together.
"Therefore, as we have opportunity, let us do good to all,
especially to those who are of the household of faith."
Praise the Lord.
The Bible says we must do good to all, especially to those of the household of faith.
Those who are to receive must learn how to plant.
Anyone who plants, the Bible says, is conscious of the future
because he will find help if he ever falls on hard times.
Anyone who plants is conscious of the future
Brethren, today is for planting and tomorrow is for reaping.
Patience is an important tool when you are planting;
you must wait for what you plant to mature.
Surely your seed will come back to you in a hundredfold.
Just as the Bible says in Psalm 37:25 that the fruit of the righteous extends to his children.
If you realise that what you do today, whether good or bad, extends to your children,
then you will be careful of what you are doing now.
If you are conscious that whatever you do today, whether good or bad, extends to your fruit,
you will be conscious of whatever you are doing now.
Whatever situation you may be facing, if you are to know a successful life,
you must learn to plant your strength, forgiveness, mercy, kindness, faithfulness and love.
You must plant them.
God is not so much concerned about what we have to give as the manner in which we give it.
If you are to know a successful life, then you must learn to plant your strength, forgiveness,
kindness, faithfulness, mercy, favour and love.
Ask the widow in the Book of Mark 12 and she will tell you
that giving is a real privilege when it is done in a proper attitude.
The Book of Mark 12 captures the irony of a situation where a poor widow is exalted
far above the high and mighty in the society - all because of her selfless generosity
The Bible says she was one of those without any legal, political, social or economic stature
but Jesus noticed her as she gave her true offering.
Even though she was in dire need, the Bible says, she never held back.
Her action shows an example of sacrificial giving.
She was the only one who understood the principle of unlimited love and faith.
Let someone say, "Unlimited love and faith".
- a poor widow.
God is most honoured in our sacrificial giving.
True giving is sacrificial indeed.
The word 'sacrifice' does not suggest a bed of roses.
When you give, when you release forgiveness, sometimes it will cost you some pain to do so.
Sacrifice does not suggest a bed of roses.
When you sacrifice, you must feel the pain.
It is better not to give than to give what is not important to you.
The Bible says that God is most honoured by our sacrificial giving
but He is dishonoured by our offering of convenience.
We want to do it at our time.
We want to do it when we wish to do it.
We want to do it in our own way.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Brethren, ask Joseph in the Book of Genesis 41 - when you have the time, read it.
Ask Joseph in that Book of Genesis 41 and he will tell you
that whatever is in your hand right now is capable of changing the course of your life.
When he found himself in the prison, the Bible says, he never waited for a more convenient time
to show himself as a commissioned solution provider, even in pain and suffering.
Whatever situation you may be facing, brethren - whether you are happy or not -
you must always remember that weeping must not hinder your sowing.
No matter what your situation looks like, no matter how you feel,
brethren, weeping must not hinder your sowing.
Remember the beauty of life does not depend on how happy or youful you are
but how happy others can be because of you.
This was what Joseph realised;
he realised that sowing seeds in faith is using what God has given to obtain what God has promised.
That is why he released forgiveness, even when he found himself in prison.
Joseph released forgiveness. The Bible says, his gift, his talent ushered him to the throne;
his gift, his talent ushered him to his divine destiny.
It therefore implies that there is no one that God has created without a gift.
There is no one that God has created without a talent.
Brethren, your care to the lonely,
viewers all over the world, your concern for the weak,
the forgiveness you show to others might be what they need for their recovery
and at the same time that might be what you need to plant to discover your own destiny.
The love you give to the needy, the compassion you show,
the concern you give, the forgiveness you release to others -
that might be what you need to discover your divine destiny
and that might be what they need to discover themselves.
That may be what they need for their own recovery.
It might be what you need to plant to discover your own destiny.
If you say you are weak, don't be surprised to see those who are weaker than you.
If you say you are poor, don't be surprised to see those who are poorer than you.
Whatever that is in your hand right now is what God will use to bless others through you.
Someone is somewhere in need of what you have in your hand for their survival.
The Bible says it is true we may not be equally gifted
but God has done it in such a way that we all have some strength to contribute to one another.
You begin to succeed with your life when the hurts and problems of others begin to matter to you.
Tell your neighbour, "You begin to succeed with your life
when the hurts and problems of others begin to matter to you".
Remember the title of our message: The Secret of Abundance.
The Bible says that God oftentimes uses men as instruments of justice,
peace, kindness, love, patience, favour.
Brethren, God is concerned about your growth.
Viewers all over the world, God is concerned about your growth.
Today, many are not growing because they fail to realise that their future is connected to people.
Many deny their future from being reshaped because they never find joy or reason in helping others.
Many deny their future from being reshaped
because they never find joy or reason in releasing forgiveness, in settling differences.
You may say you are in the business of giving but there is nothing to show for it.
You may say, "I've been helping the poor but there is nothing to show for it".
You may say, "I released forgiveness but still, there is nothing to show for it!"
You may say, "I give everything I have to the poor but there is nothing to show for it".
Check the way and manner you give it.
If you have not seen anything, check the way and manner you give it.
When you give with pride and arrogance, you honour yourself and dishonour God,
thereby magnifying yourself above your Heavenly Father.
That is why it is difficult to see the results.
When you give with pride and arrogance, the Bible says we make ourselves creditors
instead of the debtors we are.
Remember, we are all debtors, being sinners; God is our Creditor, our Provider.
Tell your neighbour, "God is concerned about your growth".
God is concerned about our growth.
Finally brethren, let's turn our Bible to the Book of 2 Corinthians 9
and let us take our reading from verse 6.
"But this I say: He who sows sparingly will also reap sparingly,
and he who sows bountifully will also reap bountifully.
So let each one give as he purposes in his heart, not grudgingly or of necessity;
for God loves a cheerful Giver."
The Bible says, as children of God, when you release the seed in your hand -
it may be the seed of forgiveness, love, compassion -
the Lord promises to take the blessing in His hand and release it to your life.
If you release the seed in your hand, brethren,
the Lord promises to take the blessing in His hand release it to your life.
This is a divine principle of a bountiful harvest that the Lord has founded
in all believers who are in their occupation of destiny.
in all of us who are in our occupation of destiny.
Remember, giving is not only in monetary terms - it may be your mercy, favour,
forgiveness, care, concern, compassion.
There are many people on the sickbed in the hospital.
Visit them, show them care, love.
Who knows - that might be what they need for their recovery.
Who knows - that might be what is needed of you to discover your divine destiny.
Whatever that is in your hand right now is enough to create the future you desire.
Tell your neighbour, "Whatever that is in my hand right now..."
Raise your hand and say, "Whatever that is in my hand right now
is capable of changing the history of my life,
is capable of changing the course of my life.
Whether small or big - it doesn't matter.
By doing this, brethren, you will discover who you are.
Vomiting Poisonous Substances
Unforgiveness causes us to ignore our offenders when they are in pain.
Many a times we see those who hurt us - they are in trouble.
We ignore them, "It is not my business.
Okay, you can see he is reaping the fruits of his labour".
Unforgiveness causes us to ignore our offenders when they are in pain, trouble;
it retaliates and rejoices when others are hurt.
It is hard for those with unforgiveness in their heart to release help to their offenders.
The Bible says, it is more blessed, more rewarding to help those who hurt you,
those who do not share the same faith with you,
those who cannot even give you back.
You can count how many times you have seen those who hurt you,
you have seen your offenders in trouble and you ignored them.
Don't be surprised when you eventually realise, perhaps too late,
that it was Jesus Himself whom you denied
Ask yourself: Do I really love God?
Let that question run in your heart: Do I really love God?
How does the love of God function in a man who only thinks, works with an empty and idle word?
Ultimately, the Bible says we are called to respond to all human needs for that is what love entails.
This does not, however, mean that our care for the needy alone is enough to bring us to salvation.
But the Bible says, it forms the basis of judging the level of our kindness.
Looking the other side when your fellow brother is in trouble is equay to rejecting Christ.
Brethren, if you are waiting for a more convenient time to release forgiveness,
if you are waiting for a more convenient time to help the weak,
to help those who are in need, that time may never come.
If you are waiting for the time when you have abundance, that time may never come.
What we give out of little means a lot to us but the Bible says it attracts God's attention.
I want to leave you with these thoughts in mind.
Viewers all over the world, I want to leave you with this one thought in mind.
You will reap the full harvest of whatever you sow if only you persevere.
Tell your neighbour, "You will reap whatever you sow if only you persevere".
May the Lord bless His Word in the midst of your heart, in Jesus' name.
Thank You, Jesus.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
RV: Mel Flowers 06/04/2019